<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Home</title>
    <link>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sales Analysis</title>
      <link>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/salesanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:25:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/salesanalysis/</guid>
      <description>In this project I use Python Pandas &amp;amp; Python Matplotlib to analyze and answer business questions about 12 months worth of sales data. The data contains hundreds of thousands of electronics store purchases broken down by month, product type, cost, purchase address, etc.
I start by cleaning the data. Tasks during this section include: Drop NaN values from DataFrame Removing rows based on a condition Change the type of columns (to_numeric, to_datetime, astype)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Failure Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/heart_failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/heart_failure/</guid>
      <description>Cardiovascular diseases (CVDs) are the number 1 cause of death globally, taking an estimated 17.9 million lives each year, which accounts for 31% of all deaths worldwide. Heart failure is a common event caused by CVDs and this dataset contains 12 features that can be used to predict mortality by heart failure.
Most cardiovascular diseases can be prevented by addressing behavioral risk factors such as tobacco use, unhealthy diet and obesity, physical inactivity and harmful use of alcohol using population-wide strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaria in Africa EDA</title>
      <link>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/malaria_in_africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/malaria_in_africa/</guid>
      <description>Africa, the world&amp;rsquo;s second-largest continent, a continent with a wide array of vibrant cultures each with its own deep history, continent number 2 of largest population, and the continent is home to wonderful wildlife you can spot when you go on safari! Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on Africa in this dataset.
Malaria is a common disease in Africa. The disease is transmitted to humans through infected mosquito bites. Although you can take preventive measures against malaria, it can be life-threatening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare Provider Fraud Detection Analysis</title>
      <link>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/healthcare_provider_fraud_detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://CrispinK.github.io/Crispin_Portfolio/post/healthcare_provider_fraud_detection/</guid>
      <description>Project Objectives
Provider Fraud is one of the biggest problems facing Medicare. According to the news, the total Medicare spending increased exponentially due to frauds in Medicare claims. Healthcare fraud is an organized crime which involves peers of providers, physicians, beneficiaries acting together to make fraud claims.
Rigorous analysis of Medicare data has yielded many physicians who indulge in fraud. They adopt ways in which an ambiguous diagnosis code is used to adopt costliest procedures and drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
